譯者:微博@Emtee
女劫
盒子
聖誕時節 和兩個孩子在城裏過一天可不容易
It's not easy spending a day in the city with two kids around Christmastime,
即使你帶他們去看了日場 玩了戶外溜冰
even if you have taken them to a matinee and outdoor skating.
我不得不和他們爭執
I'd had to fight with them,
讓他們乘3點55分回郊區的列車及時趕赴晚餐
with Danny in particular, to get them aboard the 3:55 back to the suburbs
而丹尼特別難搞
in time for dinner.
他老惦記著禮物
Presents were still in his mind.
盒子裏是什麽
What's in the box?
丹尼
Danny...
別煩那位先生
Leave the man alone.
是禮物
Present.
- 我能看看嗎 - 丹尼
- Can I see? - Danny.
別問東問西的
Stop being so nosy.
沒事 沒關係
It's okay. No problem.
我得走了 快到站了
Gotta go. My stop's next.
下一站 布魯克菲爾德
Brookfield next. Brookfield.
盒子
別這樣 丹尼 他拿的是什麽
Come on, Danny. What'd he have?
誰
Who?
那位拿著盒子的先生啊 呆子
The man, dummy, the one with the box.
盒子裏是什麽 地鐵上的那個啊
What was in the box? The one on the subway.
沒什麽
Nothin'.
沒什麽?
Nothing?
你意思是空的?
You seriously mean it was empty?
- 裏面沒什麽? - 嘿 夥計們
- There was nothing in there? - Hey, guys.
吃的好了
Chow's on.
太棒了
Great.
怎麽了 小屁孩 不餓嗎
What's the matter, squirt? Not hungry?
不餓
Not really.
你 不餓?
You, not hungry?
你總是很餓啊
You're always hungry.
你帶他們在外面吃過東西了嗎
Did you get them something to eat when you were out?
就熱巧克力
Just hot chocolate.
還有棉花糖和甘草糖
With marshmallows and licorice.
真好
Nice.
我能去玩了嗎
Can I go play?
當然
Sure.
但你要刷牙
But I want those teeth brushed.
- 好的 爸爸  - 乖
- Yeah, dad. - All right.
還要?
More?
要吃嗎 丹尼
Want some, Danny?
不要?
No?
都是我們的啦
More for us.
- 天呐 看啊 - 看啊
- Oh, my god. Look. - Oh, look.
周一
孩子們
Kids.
不要跑
No running.
不了 謝謝 媽媽
No, thanks, mom.
丹尼爾
Daniel.
怎麽了 媽媽
Yeah, mom?
別忘了你的午餐
Don't forget your lunch.
謝謝
Thanks.
怎麽了
What's going on?
- 又不餓? - 是啊
- You're not hungry again? - Nope.
今天是學校的匹薩日
It was pizza day at school.
我沒參與
No, I skipped it.
這讓我很難相信啊
I find that hard to believe.
吃吧 把肋排吃了
Come on. Eat your ribs.
不了 謝謝 我不餓
No, thank you. I'm not hungry.
周二
他帶回家的午餐又是沒吃過的
He came home with his lunch untouched again,you know.
真的嗎
Really?
他大概在食堂偷偷吃了垃圾食品什麽的
He was probably sneaking junk food in the cafeteria or something.
我覺得我們該和韋勒醫生約個時間
I think we should make an appointment with Dr. Weller.
也許他生病了
Maybe he's coming down with something.
我肯定這只是他爲了逃學而耍的花招
I'm sure it's just some stunt he's pulling to get out of going to school.
我可不會擔心
I wouldn't worry about it.
好吧 我開始擔心了
Well, I am starting to get worried.
你看 他沒發燒
Look, he doesn't have a fever.
就算他得了流感
And even if he has the flu,
韋勒醫生也沒什麽能幫到他的
there's nothing Dr. Weller can do for him anyway.
大概吧
I guess so.
聽著 夥計 你得吃些東西
Listen, buddy, you gotta eat something.
丹尼 今天你爲什麽沒吃我給你做的午餐
Danny, why didn't you eat the lunch I made you today?
我不喜歡
I didn't feel like it.
試試蒜蓉麵包吧
Try some garlic bread.
真心好吃
It's really good.
你喜歡意大利面的
You love spaghetti.
不了 謝謝
No, thanks.
你這樣已經三天了 夥計
It... it's been three days, buddy.
你身體還好嗎
Are you feeling okay?
天呐 最好沒得水痘
Oh, my god. It better not be the chickenpox.
阿曼達·迪斯伯裏得了水痘
Amanda Dewsbury had the chickenpox,
然後整整一周沒來學校
and she didn't show up for school for, like, an entire week.
她全身都是
She was covered in, like,
噁心的膿瘡...
these disgusting, oozing sores...
我挺好
I feel fine,
就是不餓
just not hungry.
好吧
Okay.
周三
吃吧 丹尼 我們做了你最愛的匹薩
Come on, Danny. We made your favorite, pizza.
快吃吧
Come on now.
不餓
Not hungry.
聞起來不錯
Smells good.
你不吃那匹薩就別想離開這張桌子
You're not getting up from this table until you eat that pizza.
懂我意思嗎
Do you understand me?
Do you understand me?!
丹尼 就吃一口吧
Please, Danny, just take one bite.
不了 謝謝
No, thank you.
你這樣够久了 丹尼
This has gone on long enough. Danny!
該死的 你吃啊
God damn it, will you just eat?!
我不餓
I'm not hungry.
好吧
Fine.
那就去睡覺吧
Then just go to bed.
周四
頭暈 嘔吐 腹瀉嗎
Any, uh, dizziness, vomiting, diarrhea?
沒 沒什麽
No, nothing.
發熱 精神不振呢
Fever, listlessness?
沒 他看上去挺好
No. He seems fine.
可你們說他五天沒吃東西了
And you say he hasn't eaten in five days?
真沒什麽
Absolutely nothing.
我可以和他單獨待會兒嗎
Can I have a moment with him, please?
當然可以
Um, yeah, sure.
- 沒問題  - 謝謝
- Sure. - Thanks.
丹尼...
Danny...
嗯?
Hmm?
你有什麽想告訴我的嗎
Is there anything you want to tell me?
你確定?我意思是...
You sure? I mean...
我是來傾聽的 我想幫助你
I'm here to listen. I wanna help.
一切都挺好
Everything's fine.
我只是不餓 就是這樣
I'm just not hungry, is all.
你得吃東西 丹尼
You gotta eat, Danny.
爲什麽
Why?
這個嘛...
Well, um...
世界各地都有人在挨餓
There's people starving all over the world.
你不吃東西的話
I mean, if you don't eat...
你最終會死
Eventually you'll die.
就這麽簡單
It's that simple.
所以?
So?
你們怎麽不早點帶他來
Why didn't you bring him in sooner?
講不清
I don't know.
比起上次體檢 他瘦了五磅
Well, he's lost five pounds since his last checkup.
除此之外 他的生理似乎沒問題
Other than that, he seems fine physically.
我們要對他做一些測試
We're gonna run some tests on him,
但願會讓我們瞭解得更清楚
and hopefully, uh, it'll give us a clearer picture.
他在學校有什麽問題嗎
Has he had any problems at school?
- 沒有 - 沒有
- No. - No.
據我們所知沒什麽
Nothing that we're aware of.
家裏呢
Home?
沒有 爲什麽這麽問
No. Why do you ask?
我覺得丹尼可能有些情緒問題
I think Danny might be having some emotional problems.
我能給你們推薦一位專家
Now, there's a specialist that I can recommend for you.
心理醫生?
A psychiatrist?
不是 是位治療師 放心
No, a therapist, and don't worry.
他不會推銷藥物給丹尼吃
He's not gonna push any pills on Danny.
他會幫助他的
He'll be there to help him.
他會怎麽幫呢 醫生
Well, how's he gonna help him, doctor?
我們要搞清問題的根源所在
Look, we're gonna get to the bottom of this.
我要你每天給我打電話
Now, what I want you to do is to call me every day
告訴我丹尼的情况
and let me know how Danny's doing,
如果他進食的話
if he's eating.
好的
Okay.
如果他不進食 也別逼他
If he's not, don't push him.
當然不會
No, of course not.
好嗎
All right?
別擔心
Stay calm.
隨時保持聯繫
I'll keep you posted.
- 謝謝 韋勒醫生  - 謝謝
- Thanks, Dr. Weller. - Thanks.
說不通啊
It doesn't make any sense.
嘿
Hey.
你們在聊什麽
What are you guys talking about?
- 沒什麽  - 沒什麽
- Nothing. - Nothing.
別這樣 你們剛在聊什麽
Come on. What were you just talking about?
就聊點事
Just stuff.
秘密的事?
Secret stuff?
就聊點事
Just, you know, stuff.
或許是跟你爲何不進食有關的事?
Stuff that maybe has to do with why you're not eating?
這種事?
That kind of stuff?
好吧
Fine.
睡覺吧
Let's get back to bed.
珍妮 有什麽事嗎
Jenny, what's the matter?
沒什麽
Nothing.
晚安 媽媽
Good night, mom.
珍妮
Jenny.
周五
來了
Coming.
嘿 媽媽
Hey, mom.
嘿
Hey.
怎麽了 媽媽
Yeah, mom?
- 巧克力  - 不用
- It's chocolate. - I'm okay.
我不餓 謝謝
I'm not hungry. Thanks.
珍妮呢
Where's Jenny?
她說她不餓
She says she's not hungry.
爲什麽
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也想知道
I wish I did.
你有重視這些事嗎
Are you taking any of this seriously?
當然
Of course I am.
我是他們的母親
I'm their mother.
好吧 那我真的不明白
Well, I just don't understand it.
明白什麽
Understand what?
我們孩子在挨餓
How you can eat
你怎麽吃得下
while our children are starving.
我必須吃東西啊 不是嗎
Well, I have to eat, don't I?
丹尼
Danny.
嘿
Hey.
你和珍妮怎麽了
What is going on with you and Jenny?
你可以跟我說
Y... you know you can tell me.
跟我說吧
Please, tell me.
他說什麽了
What did he say?
啊?
Huh?
丹尼
Danny.
沒什麽
Nothing.
這片給你
Piece for you.
這片是你的
好了
There you go.
聖誕節
我記得那天的歡笑
I remember laughter from that day,
滿是歡笑
plenty of laughter.
沒人的新衣服是合身的
Nobody's new clothes fit,
但我們依然試著穿上
but we tried them on anyway.
不管你信不信 我們那時很開心
Believe it or not, we were happy.
我們以前從未如此和睦
We were more together than we had ever been.
丹尼
Danny...
你還記得那天在列車上
Do you remember that day on the train...
那位拿著盒子的先生嗎
The man with the box?
你還記得你往盒子裏看過嗎
Do you remember looking inside the box?
記得
Yeah.
裏面是什麽
What was in it?
沒什麽
Nothing.
真的是沒什麽?
Really nothing?
你是說真的是空的?
You mean it was actually empty?
但我以爲...
But I thought I...
我記得他說那是份禮物
I remember him saying it was a present.
他是在開什麽玩笑嗎
Was he playing some kind of a joke?
是玩笑嗎
I mean, is this some kind of a joke?
丹尼在1月17日去世了
Danny died on January 17th.
珍妮在2月3日走了
Jenny went on February third,
我丈夫羅伯挺到了27日
and my husband Robert lingered until the 27th.
在經歷這一切的日子裏
And through all of this,
在經歷這一切的數個星期裏
through all these weeks now,
我每天都來回于醫院
going back and forth to the hospital each day...
尋找他
I look for him.
我得找到他
I need to find him...
我要知道我兒子知道了什麽 把什麽傳給了其他人
To know what my son knew and then passed on to the others.
這是我唯一能瞭解他們的辦法
It's the only way I can get close to them now.
我想看看
I want to see.
我必須看看
I have to see.
我餓了
I'm hungry.
生日派對
嘖
Tsk.
早上好 卡拉
Good morning, Carla.
謝謝
Oh, thank you.
還一小時不到 客人就要到了
The guests will be getting here in less than an hour.
我讓露西多睡會兒 她一直睡不好
I let Lucy sleep in. She hasn't been sleeping well.
你要我去叫醒她?
You want me to wake her?
15分鐘內 她還沒起來就去叫醒她吧
Um, guess maybe wake her in 15 if she's not up yet.
好的
Okay.
那是給大衛準備的嗎
Is that for David?
是啊
Yeah.
不用了 我覺得蘭普頓先生
No, I don't think Mr. Lampton
不會來過他女兒的生日
will be joining us at his daughter's birthday.
我早上到這時 他的車也在
His car was here when I got in this morning.
他一定比我早到
Must have gotten in late.
不會的
No. No.
他出行在外還沒回來
He's not back from his trip yet.
也許他出去跑步了
Maybe he's out for a run.
我真不這麽認爲
I really doubt it.
他要來的話 我昨晚就知道了
I think I would know if he had come in last night.
當然 我不是...
Yes, of course. I didn't...
他的也給我吧
Okay. I... well, I'll just take his, too.
可別浪費了
No use letting it go to waste.
你能不能
Can you, um...
把客廳壁櫃裏的桌布
Get the table runner from the hall closet,
放到邊桌上
and, uh, just put it on the side table.
禮物和賀卡就放那邊
I think we're gonna do gifts and cards over there.
好的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
不好意思
Ooh, sorry.
大衛
David.
天呐 你和卡拉
God, between you and Carla,
是想讓我心臟病發作嗎
you're gonna give me a heart attack.
你都沒說要來
You know, I didn't even hear you come in.
我都不知道
I don't know.
不過我很高興你回來了
Anyway, I'm just so glad that you're back.
我真的希望這事能順利
I really, really want this to go well.
露西一直很焦慮
Lucy has been having such anxiety,
我真的希望這能讓她擺脫自我禁錮
and I'm just really hoping that this brings her out of her shell.
她的治療師
Do you know her therapist
說她看到我才焦慮的
says that she gets her anxiety from watching me?
我?你敢信?
Me? Can you believe it?
簡直扯淡
I mean, the nerve.
只是...算了 無所謂
It's just... anyway, it doesn't matter.
你來了她會很高興的
She's gonna be so glad that you made it.
大衛?
David?
大衛
David...
媽媽
Mom!
Mommy!
你在哪
Where are you?
嗨
Hi.
我就在這啊 熊猫
I'm right here, panda.
早上好 生日快樂
Good morning. Happy birthday.
今天是我的生日
It's my birthday.
我知道 我知道 今天是你的生日
I know. I know. It is your birthday.
我出了意外
I had an accident.
小露 出什麽事了
Oh, no. Oh, Luce, what happened?
沒事的
It's gonna be okay.
好嗎
All right?
沒事的
Everything's gonna be okay.
你會好的
You're gonna be okay.
好了
All right.
好 我們就...
Okay. We'll just...
找另一套服裝吧
Go find another costume.
好了
There we go.
可怕的鬼
Scary ghost.
一點都不可怕
It's not scary at all.
我看上去好傻
I look stupid.
親愛的 你看上去不傻
Sweetheart, you don't look stupid.
你看上去棒極了
You look great.
我覺得真會嚇到人
I think it's gonna really be scary.
好了
There you go.
嚇到我了 可怕的鬼
Got me, scary ghost.
你去找卡拉 給她看看吧
Why don't you go find Carla and show her?
現在我是個死掉的女孩
Now I am a dead girl.
大衛...
Oh, David...
你個白痴
You idiot.
找到了嗎
Did you find them?
找到了 我說了會找到的
Yes, dear. I told you I would.
我不知道你爲什麽一直把東西藏你爸辦公室
I don't know why you keep hiding things in daddy's office.
你知道我們碰他東西 他會怎麽樣
You know how he gets when we touch his things.
我知道 媽媽在哪
I know. Where's mom at?
大概在某處擺正一副畫
Probably straightening a painting somewhere.
啊?
Huh?
來
Come on.
我們去外面把畫畫完
Let's go outside and finish that drawing.
外面可比這沉悶的房子裏面好多了
It's too nice outside to be in this stuffy house.
天呐
Oh, my god.
瑪麗
Mary?
你在裏面嗎
Are you in there?
卡拉跟我說
Carla told me
你在這裏忙活
you were futzing around back here.
瑪麗
Mare?
我得和你談會兒 親愛的
I just need to speak with you for a moment, dear.
我知道你在忙著準備派對什麽的
I know you're busy with the party prep and all.
瑪麗
Mare?
Mary?
你在那啊
Oh, there you are.
嗨 馬德琳
Hi, Madeleine.
嗨 早上好
Hi. Good morning.
你在地上幹嘛
What are you doing down there?
我只是...
Oh, I was just, uh...
在修地毯
Fixing the carpet.
後面是什麽
What have you got back there?
肯定是給露西生日準備的大東西
Something big for Lucy's birthday, no doubt.
你認識街對面的蒂莉·安德森?
You know Tilly Anderson from across the street?
她女兒格維尼芬
They got her daughter Gwinnifer,
- 那個胖胖的小傢伙...  - 是的
- that little chubby thing... - Yes.
他們讓一個歐洲設計師
They had a designer in Europe
給她造了個公主馬車床
build her a Princess coach bed
裏面配上了平面電視
complete with flat-screen TV built in.
搞得就像她比現在
Like she needs to be laying around
更得躺在電視機前
in front of the TV any more than she already does.
真可憐 祝福她
Poor thing, bless her heart,
她上初中
she's gonna have a rough go of it
會很艱難
come junior high.
我跟蒂莉說 她得讓她
I told Tilly she needs to get her
去費爾蒙特那個給未滿13歲孩子上的新普拉提班
into that new Pilates for preteens class over on Fairmont.
我能爲你做什麽 馬德琳
What can I... what can I do for you, Madeleine?
我知道今天是露西的生日
Well, it's just I know that it's Lucy's birthday today,
我的繼女從佛蒙特州的
and I know that my stepdaughters are away
新寄宿學校回來了
at that new boarding school in Vermont, you know,
就是陽光山丘的那所 非常高檔 非常難進
in sunny hill. Very exclusive, very hard to get into.
只是整個社區
But it's just the entire neighborhood,
好像都在談論這個派對的事 所以...
it seems to be talking about this party, so...
你想來參加派對嗎 馬德琳
Would you like to come to the party, Madeleine?
那太好了 親愛的
Oh! Why, that'd be lovely, dear.
- 謝謝邀請  - 好了
- Thanks so much for the invite. - Yeah. Okay.
上個月 徹斯納特的吉布森一家...
You know, last month, the Gibsons over on Chestnut...
- 行了 - 他們叫了個DJ
- No. - They had a deejay,
完全就是個魔術主題歡樂屋
an entire magic-themed fun house.
- 天呐 - 你有爲露西準備什麽特別的嗎
- Oh, gosh. - Are you doing anything special for Lucy?
就她的朋友 還有蛋糕
It's just her friends and cake.
所以 嗯哼
So, mm-hmm.
你要我帶什麽儘管說
Well, let me know if you want me to get anything.
真的不麻煩 有個設計師開的紙杯蛋糕店...
It's really no trouble. There's a designer cupcake place...
- 好了 過會兒見 - 就在我給猫洗澡那地方的旁邊
- All right, see you in a bit. - Over by where I get the cats washed.
好的 有需要就說 謝謝了 親愛的
Okay. Just... Just let me know. Thanks, dear.
該死
Fuck.
馬德琳 看在...
Oh, Madeleine, for the love of...
什麽...
What the...
嘿 我還沒唱完
Well, hey, I wasn't done yet.
還有三段正歌要唱
I got, like, three more verses to go.
你那套服裝 我出200美元要了
I'll give you $200 for the suit.
不行 你就按下播放 然後...
Well, nah, just hit play, and...
我不是...我不是露西 好嗎
I'm not... I'm not Lucy, okay?
露西是我女兒 所以你不用擔心
Lucy's my daughter, so you don't have to worry.
必須是露西來看
I think it's gotta be Lucy.
你沒在聽我說話 300 你想要300?
You're not listening. 300. You want 300?
這套服裝有付首期
Ah, there's a down payment on the suit,
今天下午我還得用
and I got a thing this afternoon.
- 我... - 1000美元
- I... - $1,000.
1000美元 外加兩盎司我去年膝蓋手術用的藥用大麻
$1,000 and two ounces of medical marijuana from my knee surgery last year.
媽媽
Mom!
媽媽 你在哪
Mom, where are you?!
他們來了 他們來了 他們來了
They're here! They're here! They're here!
快來 快來 你在哪
Come on! Come on! Where are you?
他們來了 開派對咯
They're here! Party time!
馬上 親愛的
Just a minute, darling.
我來了
I'm coming.
生日派對
或
露西被壓抑的七歲生日記憶
...真不是她媽媽的錯
（即使她的治療師說這大概就是她害怕親昵的原因）
別摔下去
等等 我們怎麽知道
Wait. How are we gonna know
這條路對不對
if it is or if it isn't the right way?
我有個百靈百驗的內置指南針
I have an internal compass that has failed me never.
等下 所以白蝎子是危險的?
Wait.So the white scorpion is the dangerous one?
當心透亮的蝎子就行了
Just look out for translucent scorpions.
我覺得所有蝎子
I feel like all scorpions
都很可能有危險
are probably dangerous.
沒錯 我意思是 它們都傷人
Yeah, I mean, they all hurt,
但蝎子顔色越淺
but the lighter the color the scorpion,
就越危險
the more dangerous it is.
我根本不會擔心黑色的
I wouldn't even worry about the black ones.
當心脚下就行
Just watch your step.
保羅 我感覺你對我一直這樣
Paul, I feel like you do this to me all the time.
我們小的時候 你跟我說
Like when we were kids and you told me that...
蜘蛛會在我臉上咬
The spider was gonna bite me in the face
然後産卵
and then lay eggs
然後這些幼蛛
and then these baby spiders
會在半夜從我皮膚裏孵化出來
were gonna hatch out of my skin in the middle of the night.
因爲是會這樣
'Cause that shit happens.
不會的
No, it doesn't.
我一周都沒睡 這很瘮人
I didn't sleep for a week. That's not even cute.
五年級時 杰米·普雷斯頓的弟弟就出了這種事
That happened to Jamie Preston's brother in the fifth grade.
- 我向上帝發誓  - 杰米·普雷斯頓?
- Hand to god. - Jamie Preston?
有皮疹的那孩子嗎
That was the kid with the rash?
不是 那是他表弟
No, that was his cousin.
別摔下去
怎麽樣
Huh?
天呐
Oh, my god.
這太他媽棒了
This is so fucking epic.
是吧
Right?
所以你們
This is why you guys
應該每年都讓我做計劃
should let me do the planning every year.
保羅 那我們最後都會在拉斯維加斯脫衣舞俱樂部了
Paul, we'd end up in a strip club in Vegas.
還會有去路易斯安那烟酒掃貨游
Some booze cruise in Louisiana.
沒錯 這怎麽樣 說真的
Yes, how good was that, though? Seriously?
哇哦 這裏真高
Wow. We're really high up here.
- 別摔下去  - 住手
- Don't fall. - - Stop!
這一點也不好玩
That's not funny!
寶貝 放鬆 我護著你呢
Oh, babe, relax. I had you.
你幹嘛要那樣
Why would you do that?
我護著她了 所以只是個開大了的玩笑
Because I had her, so it was a great joke.
寶貝 你真的很惱火嗎
Baby, are you seriously mad?
是吧
Right?
- 沒錯 - 是的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
想拍照嗎
You want a picture?
- 想 - 好的
- Yep. - Okay.
好了
Okay.
你幹嘛
What are you doing?
- 我只是...  - 正常點就行了
- I'm just... - Just be normal.
正常點
Be normal.
我只是太熱了
Ah, it's just really hot,
你知道我恐高
and you know I'm afraid of heights.
什麽時候的事
Since when?
什麽叫什麽時候的事
What do you mean, "since when"?
你一直都知道
Since forever.
- 對不起  - 我很累
- I'm sorry. - I'm, like, tired,
我在和大自然交流
and I'm communing with nature.
- 好的 好的  - 我有一...
- Okay. Okay. - I have, like, one mo...
你在看什麽
What are you looking at?
天呐
Oh, my god!
- 是蝎子嗎 - 不是
- Is it a scorpion?! - No!
我討厭蝎子
I hate scorpions.
是白色的嗎
Is it white?
對不起
I'm sorry.
這次我不是在和你胡鬧
That time, I wasn't fucking with you.
- 你沒事吧 - 她沒事
- You okay? - She's fine.
說真的 這堵墻上的東西很詭异 - 你沒事吧
- Seriously something creepy on this wall. - You okay?
- 怎麽了 - 我沒事
- What happened? - Yeah, I'm fine.
看啊
Look.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
真棒
Ah, cool.
這是什麽意思
What does it mean?
滾出我的草地?
"Get off my lawn"?
不是 他們把它們畫墻上
No, they paint them into the walls
是用來標記領土的
to mark their territory.
像是古代幫派標志
Like ancient gang signs.
他們是誰
Who's they?
印第安人?
Indians?
保羅 是美洲原住民
Paul, it's "native American."
你應該這麽說
That's the... What you're supposed to say.
要古老多了
Older than that,
肯定早于美洲原住民
predates native Americans for sure.
那看起來像血
That looks like blood.
噁心
Gross.
好了 要在天黑前回去的話 就該走了
Well, all righty. Time to get moving if we're gonna get back by dark.
等下 早于美洲原住民
Wait. Wouldn't people native to America
在美洲土生土長的人
before the native Americans
不會被稱爲美洲原住民?
be called native Americans?
不一定
Not necessarily.
可能是早期智人
Could be early homo sap
也可能是新人類
or homo novus,
取决于你認同哪種歷史學說
depending on what theory of history you subscribe to.
就是這樣 老兄
This is it, man.
就我們和星星
It's just us and the stars
這是整個周末最棒的遠足
and the best hiking around all weekend.
是啊
Yeah.
很棒
It's nice.
我在公園定的
That glamping place
那個豪華野營的地方
that I booked in the... in the park,
也很棒
that was also really nice.
有淋浴室
That had showers.
還有尖叫的孩子
And it had screaming children.
有你走著不會沒方向的路...
And paths where you can walk and not get lost and...
還有兄弟會學生用被壓壞的啤酒罐做的路標
Trail markers made of crushed natural ice cans from frat bros.
沒錯 謝謝
Exactly. Thank you.
這是附近最好的營地 好嗎
This is the best campsite around, okay,
根本就沒人知道這地方
and nobody even knows about it.
你是怎麽知道的
How'd you know about it?
我就是知道 好嗎
I just know shit, man, okay?
我和大自然交流
I commune with nature,
它爲我指引道路
and it shows me the way.
它爲他指引道路
It shows him the way.
或是他買通了最後個加油站那兒的夥計才知道的
Or he bribed the gas station guy at the last stop.
這也是
And also that.
- 什麽  - 確實如此
- What?! - That's true.
- 你在逗我嗎 保羅  - 怎麽了
- Are you kidding me? Paul! - What?
我們在這裏可能是非法的
It could be, like, illegal for us to be out here.
很明顯 這裏是個歷史遺産地
This is like a historical heritage site, clearly.
- 我們可能會因此被捕  - 拜托
- You know, we could get arrested for that. - Oh, come on.
怎麽了 你覺得他們想要人們
What? You think they want people
在那些古代壁畫上噴繪鶏巴嗎
spray-painting dicks on those ancient murals?
是象形文字
Hieroglyphs.
是岩刻
Petroglyphs.
埃及文才是象形文字
Hieroglyphs are Egyptian.
天呐 有時我可真是討厭你
Oh, my god. I hate you so much sometimes.
我覺得這裏很長時間沒人來了
I don't think anyone's been up here in a long time.
或許這裏被詛咒了
Maybe it's cursed.
不會的 你覺得這裏被詛咒了?
It's not... You think it's cursed?
那是什麽
What was that?
- 別去 保羅 別去 - 我去查看下
- No, Paul, don't do that. - I'll check it out.
別去 保羅 別去啊 該死
No, no. Paul, please don't do that. Fuck.
-  格雷琴 別...  - 保羅 別...
- Gretch, don't... - Paul, please don't...
天呐 我被抓到了 快跑啊
Oh, my god! It's got me! Oh! Run!
格雷琴 別理他 不然他就更起勁
Gretch, don't entertain him. You're just encouraging him.
我知道 我當然知道他是在...
I know. I fucking know he's...
他是在戲弄我 我知道
He's razzing me. I got it. I know.
保羅
Paul?
他他媽去哪了
Where the fuck did he go?
不知道 保羅 別這樣 夥計
I don't know. Paul, come on, dude.
我可不會來找你
I'm not... I'm not coming to get you.
他老這樣
He does this.
還記得他在阿迪朗達克也這樣嗎
You remember he did this in the Adirondacks?
他先走失 然後扭傷了他那該死的脚踝
He, like, wandered off, and then he, like, broke his fucking ankle.
- 我只是開個玩笑 - 別這樣 保羅
- I was just kidding. - Don't, Paul.
- 這他媽一點都不好玩 - 怎麽了
- That's not fucking funny. - What?
你是愛我的 別這樣
You love me. Come on.
好了 我們別和她胡鬧了
Okay, we're done fucking with her.
說真的 我去睡了
Seriously. I'm going to bed.
什麽 別啊
What? No!
還早呢 我只是胡鬧一下
It's so early. I was just fucking around.
我感覺不舒服
I'm not feeling good.
你的手怎麽樣了
How's your hand?
不知道 很刺痛
I don't know. It stings.
你能塗些外傷抗菌藥膏
You can put some neosporin on that.
可能會被感染
It might get infected.
你的臉被感染了
Your face is infected.
被感染?
Infected?
好吧 外傷抗菌藥膏在哪
Okay. Where's the neosporin?
我包裏有一些 要我帶你拿嗎
I have some in my bag. You want me to show you?
- 不用 我能找到  - 好的
- No, I can get that. - All right.
睡個好覺
Sleep well.
愛你哦
Love you.
天啊
Oh, man.
我喝得太醉了 夥計們
I got way too stoned, you guys.
不是吧
Oh, no.
這他媽什麽東西
What the fuck?
格雷琴
Gretch?
格雷琴 你在幹嘛
Gretchen, what are you doing?
嘿 你還好嗎
Hey, are you okay?
杰 我們不該來這的
Jay. We shouldn't be here.
嘿 格雷琴 你...
Hey. Gretchen, what is...
你...
What's...
你怎麽了
What's wrong with you?
格雷琴
Gretchen?
你們不該來這裏
You shouldn't be here.
什麽情况 老兄
What the fuck, man?
- 杰 出什麽事了 - 杰
- Jay, what's happening? - Jay.
你...幾點了 怎麽...
What are you... What time is it? What...
杰 他媽的出什麽事了
Jay, what the fuck is happening?
我不知道 我不知道 我們必須走了
I don't know! I don't know! We have to go!
格雷琴在哪
Where's Gretchen?
- 杰 你在...  - 格雷琴
- Jay, what are you... - Gretch?
- 你在幹嘛 - 杰
- What are you doing? - Jay!
這他媽的什麽情况 說話啊
What the fuck is going on?! Say something!
停 停 停
Whoa! Stop, stop, stop!
杰 夥計 別開車 她受傷了
Jay. Whoa, dude. No, no, no, no! She's hurt!
- 等等 - 他媽的放開我 那是我妹妹
- Wait! Wait! Wait! - Get the fuck off me.That's my sister.
天呐
Oh, my god.
格雷琴 格雷琴
Gretchen! Gretchen!
太他媽糟糕了
This is so fucked.
我們現在必須離開 好嗎 你不能出去
We have to leave now, okay? You can't go out there.
我爲什麽不能出去 她他媽的受傷了啊
Why can't I go out there?! She's fucking hurt!eetme#obiewybdetalsnart
聽著 相信我
Listen. Trust me.
- 你想幹嘛- 相信我就是了
- What is your deal? - Just trust me.
我不會丟下格雷琴離開的
I'm not leaving without Gretchen.
好了
Okay.
噓
Shh.
別這樣
Please. Ah...
開門 開門
Open the door. Open the door.
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
不要 不要
No. No.
格雷琴 是我
Gretchen, it's me.
是我
It's me.
translated by weibo - Emtee
她唯一活著的兒子
所以你是相信我的? 醫生
So you believe me, doctor?
你真相信我?
You actually believe me?
我相信人有計劃
I believe people have agendas.
也相信這世界是瘋狂的 我發誓
This crazy world, I swear.
我會去個他們永遠找不到我的地方
I'll go somewhere they'll never, ever find me
也永遠找不到小安迪或珍妮
or little Andy or Jenny.
祝你諸事順遂...
Godspeed to you, Mrs....
別說下去
No.
她不存在了
She's gone.
18年後
她唯一活著的兒子
來 來
Come on. Come on.
愚蠢的動物
Dumb beast.
明晚的晚餐你想要什麽特別的嗎
You want anything special for dinner tomorrow night?
也許我會烤只鶏
Maybe I'll roast a chicken.
18歲
18.
毫無意義
Doesn't make sense.
當然有
Sure it does.
我被生出來 現在我長大了
I was born. Now I'm grown up.
快長大了
Almost grown up.
在你有决定權之前
Give me one more day to be your mom
多給我一天時間做你媽媽
before you get to vote.
你真是多愁善感
You're just sentimental.
我們可以看那部爸爸出演的新電影
We could see that new movie that dad is in.
你生日想做的
Ohh. Of all the things you wanna do for your birthday,
就這個?
that's it?
你有需要時 他在哪
Where has he ever been for you?
我們老躲著他
How can he be there for me
他要怎麽才能在我身邊
when we're always hiding from him?
野心會變成邪惡的東西 親愛的
Ambition can be an evil thing, honey.
他寧願當個好萊塢的花花公子
He'd rather be a Hollywood playboy
也不願當個稱職的父親 我們躲著是有原因的
than a real father to you, and we're hiding for a reason.
別又來這套 我得走了 媽媽
Not this again. I gotta go, mom.
他的人生之中不配擁有你
He doesn't deserve to have you in his life.
今天我會去見你老師
I'm meeting with your teacher today.
隨你想幹嘛
Do whatever you want.
我們得談談在學校發生的事
We need to talk about what happened at school.
去吧 看看他們怎麽說
Go ahead. See what they say.
腌魚?
Kipper?
怎麽了 小夥子
What is it, boy?
要優惠券嗎
Want your coupons?
沒理由不要
Might as well.
金槍魚買一送一 最好的
Can't beat two-for-one tuna fish.
安迪有沒到够讓你離家
So, um, is Andy old enough
去鎮上待一晚的年紀
to let you out of the house for a night on the town?
這建議不錯
Well, that's... That's a nice suggestion,
- 但我不覺得...  - 我知道
- but I don't think... - I know.
你太忙了
You're too busy.
出于自尊心
Ah, out of self-respect,
我至少一年得試一次
I have to try at least once a year.
我只是覺得你能改變下生活節奏 就是這樣
I just thought you could use a change of pace, is all.
謝謝 切特
I appreciate that, Chet.
你真好 爲我著想
It's kind of you to think of me.
你似乎過得很不容易
Seems like you haven't had it easy,
而你因爲你孩子 一直做得很好
and you've always done good by your kid.
我上班要遲到了
I'm late for my shift.
這事故很不幸
The incident was unfortunate,
但我們覺得無需...
but nothing that we feel requires...
不幸?先生 你嗑藥了嗎
Unfortunate? Sir, are you on drugs?
沒必要說這種有敵意的話 維瑟斯夫人
Now, there's no call for that kind of hostile language, Mrs. withers.
這太瘋狂了
This is insane.
你兒子把我女兒的指甲掰掉了
Your son tore my daughter's fingernails off,
把它們完全掰掉了
tore them clear off.
她不得不進急診室
She had to go to the emergency room,
她的雙手大量出血
her hands were bleeding so badly.
我只是不明白
I just don't understand
他爲什麽會做這樣的事情
why he would do something like that.
"因爲我喜歡"
"Because I felt like it."
他就是這麽跟斯泰西說的
That's what he told Stacy.
可他從來不是一個暴力或殘忍的...
He's just never been a violent or cruel...
我聽說過些事
I hear the stories.
我聽說過他逼迫其他孩子做的事
I hear about the things he makes the other kids do,
都是以進入酷圈子的名義做的
all in the name of being in the cool clique.
維瑟斯夫人 那安迪口中的呢
Mrs. withers, what about Andy's side of the story?
誰能說他不是在某個時刻被激怒的
I mean, who's to say he wasn't provoked at some point?
你是在暗示這是斯泰西的錯嗎
Are you suggesting that this is Stacy's fault?
像這種魯莽的青少年之間的衝突...
Conflicts like these between hotheaded teenagers...
斯泰西在這所學校努力成爲畢業生代表
Stacy is on her way to being valedictorian at this school.
我很難把她稱為...
I would hardly call her...
往往是很複雜的情况
are often very complicated situations.
就不是那種你所描述的非黑即白
It's just not as black-and-white as you're describing it.
我搞不懂
I am at a loss.
他應該被停課
He should be suspended from school
或開除
or expelled.
你要我們怎麽做
What are you suggesting we do?
我覺得如果斯泰西...
I think it would be helpful if Stacy...
離校休息會很有幫助
Takes a break from school,
也可以放假 如果你願意的話 直到塵埃落定
vacation, if you will, until the dust settles.
今天下午晚些時候 你可以等我們律師的電話了
You can expect a call from our lawyer later this afternoon.
你對我們家一直都挺好 科拉
You've always been decent to our family, Cora,
但你兒子真的需要幫助
but your son needs real help.
如果你看不到
And if you can't see that,
那顯然你也需要
apparently so do you.
我很抱歉你不得不目睹別人發火
I apologize that you had to witness that outburst.
你們...
You're...
不打算懲罰他?
Not going to punish him?
你們必須做些什麽
You have to do something,
否則他永遠不會明白
or he's never going to get the message.
我們沒那打算
No, we don't.
安迪向我們發出了一條信息
You see, Andy has sent a message to us.
在這所學校過去四年的歷程中
Over the course of these past four years at this school,
安迪展現了他自己
Andy has revealed himself
是個真正了不起的人物
to be a truly remarkable human being.
一個奇才 真的
A prodigy, really.
有時
You see, every now and then,
與我們相遇的某個人
someone crosses our path
會改變我們已知的世界
who will change the world as we know it.
安迪就是其中之一
Andy is one of those people.
我希望你能支持我們的努力
I hope you will support all of our efforts
來保護他的極爲特別之處
to protect what makes him so very special.
你能來訪 我們很高興
We're so pleased that you could visit.
實踐後去魯迪家 明天回來 安迪留
生日快樂
你沒事吧 親愛的
You all right, hon?
你看上去很不好
You don't look so good.
我覺得我的羊水破了
I think my water broke.
用力 親愛的 用力
Push, honey. Push!
就是這樣
That's it.
是個男孩
It's a boy.
他是個小天使
He's a little angel.
不
No!
安迪
Andy?
誰和你在裏面
Who's in there with you?
天呐 出什麽事了
My god, what happened?
你知道我生日想要什麽嗎 媽媽
You know what I want for my birthday, mom?
隱私 我他媽的想要隱私
Privacy. I want some fucking privacy!
安迪 你跟我說你會在外面過夜
Andy, you told me that you'd be out for the night.
我被嚇到了 我不知道誰...
I was scared. I didn't know who...
我不知道誰...
I didn't know who...
生日快樂 親愛的
Happy birthday, honey.
今晚別等我了 媽媽
Don't wait up for me tonight, mom.
疲憊的人沒時間休息 我說得對嗎
No rest for the weary. Am I right?
切特 我...
Chet. I am...
有一點疲憊
A little weary.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
爲什麽哭喪著臉 科拉 今天是美好的一天
Why so glum, Cora? Today's a beautiful day.
安迪有些變化
Something's happening to Andy,
可怕的那種
something just terrible.
他只是在長大 僅此而已
Ah, now, he's just growing up, is all,
- 變成一個男人  - 不是
- becoming a man. - No!
他不再是我的安迪了
He's not my Andy anymore.
但他真的從來都不是 對嗎
But he never really was, was he?
什麽 什麽意思
What? What do you mean?
我覺得你越跟他較勁 就只會讓情况變糟
I think it'll just get messy the harder you fight him.
但問題是 我不想和他吵架
But that's just it. I don't wanna fight with him.
- 他是我的兒子  - 不是
- He's my son. - No.
是別再對抗他
Stop fighting him.
安迪的生父很快就要來認領他了
Andy's real father is coming to claim him soon.
安迪的父親對他沒興趣
Andy's father has no interest in him.
他靠每個港口都有個女孩的電影布景爲生
He lives on movie sets with a girlfriend in every port.
我無法想像你前任在達成協議時
I can't imagine your ex really understood
真明白他所達成的協議
the agreement he made back when he made it.
協議?
The agreement?
他提供了你
He offered you.
你覺得他把你提供給了誰呢
Who do you think he offered you to?
你都想起來了嗎
Is it all coming back to you...
"科拉"
"Cora"?
當然
Of course,
我沒親歷
I wasn't there.
我只是無數次地聽說過這個故事
I only heard the story a thousand times,
我覺得這個故事隨著時間的推移而被歪曲了
and I suppose the story gets distorted over time,
但它發生了
but it happened.
而我做出了我的貢獻
And I have made my contribution.
我願意相信
I'd like to believe
我對這一切産生了重大影響
that I've made a difference in all this.
這些年來
I have been blessed
我一直被祝福著看守你
to watch over you all these years.
不 不
No. No!
看守安迪
And to watch over Andy,
來讓世界準備好迎接這個榮耀之日
to prepare the world for this glorious day!
沒有什麽可害怕的 科拉
There's nothing to be afraid of, Cora!
這是他的時代了 僅此而已
It's his time, is all!
贊美...
Praise...
贊美他的黑暗 贊美他的黑暗
Praise his darkness. Praise his darkness.
安迪 看著我
Andy, look at me.
今天有個女士向我走來
Some lady came up to me today,
直呼我的名字
called me by my name.
我以前從沒見到過她
Never seen her before in my life.
安迪 看著我
Andy, look at me.
她說她認識我父親...
She said she knows my father...
說他等了我很久了
Said he's been waiting for me for a long time.
安迪 我是你的母親
Andy, I am your mother,
我要你看著我
and I demand that you look at me.
她說我是他唯一活著的兒子
She said I was his only living son.
誰的兒子 媽媽
Whose son, mom?
你跟我說爸爸再婚了
You told me dad was remarried and living
在好萊塢和他自己的孩子生活
in Hollywood with kids of his own.
沒錯
He is.
我離開他之後 他有過三任妻子
He's had three wives since I left him.
- 她是什麽意思 媽媽 - 我不知道
- What does she mean, mom? - I don't know.
- 她瘋了  - 她是什麽意思 媽媽
- She's crazy. - What does she mean, mom?
她說的沒有任何意思
What she said means nothing.
你是我的兒子 你聽到了嗎
You are my son. Do you hear me?
我們一個又一個地換鎮住
We have not lived in town after town,
避開這樣的人是有原因的
running from people like this for no reason.
他們是邪惡的 他們有個計劃
They're evil. They have an agenda.
不要聽那些話
Don't listen to those words.
你很特別
You're special.
沒錯 你一直...
You are. You always...
我不止是這樣 媽媽
I'm more than that, mom!
有時我只想傷害你...
Sometimes, I just wanna hurt you...
把你撕成碎片
Rip you to pieces.
別說這種話
Don't say things like that.
我夢想有個痛苦帝國
I have dreams of an empire of misery.
親愛的 請別再說這種話
Oh, honey, please stop saying things like that.
我要你跪下
I want you to kneel.
什麽
What?
我說跪下
I said kneel.
在我面前跪下
Kneel before me.
就是這樣
That's it.
現在爬向我
Now crawl to me.
親愛的
Oh, honey.
現在我想去和爸爸生活
I wanna go live with dad now.
你是我的孩子
You're my boy.
你永遠是我的孩子
You'll always be my boy.
你有我呢 親愛的
I've got you, honey.
別看他
Don't look at him.
閉上你的眼睛就好
Just close your eyes.
聽我講故事
Listen to the story.
譯者：微博@Emtee
起初 你讓我很不舒服
At first, you made me so unwell.
天啊 我從沒感覺像前三個月那麽糟
God, I had never felt so awful as those first three months.
我吃的是生肝和鹹餅乾
I ate raw liver and saltines,
其他的 我什麽都吃不下去
and other than that, I couldn't keep a thing down.
你汲取我的生命
You just took the life out of me,
不斷地汲取
and you took and took
直到有一天 我說 "我受够了"
until one day, I said, "I've had enough."
我發誓 親愛的
And I swear, honey,
你在我肚子深處 聽見我哭了
deep in my belly, you heard me cry.
你聽見我是多麽痛苦
You heard how much pain I was in,
因爲無論你父親是誰
because you and I are bonded,
你和我都彼此羈絆
no matter who your father is.
這種反常行爲
The perversion.
是他們對我做的邪惡之事
It's something unholy they did to me.
等我發現後
And when I found out
那些變態想把你占爲己有
those sick people wanted you for their own,
我去看了醫生
I went to the doctor
我應該第一時間去看的
I should have seen in the first place,
我跟他講了我們的瘋狂故事
and I told him our crazy story,
安迪 安迪 他相信了我
and Andy, Andy, he believed me.
他給了我們足够離開那城市的錢
And he gave us enough money to leave the city,
自那以後 我們一直在躲避
and we've been running ever since.
那醫生的恩情 證明了上帝的存在 安迪
That doctor's kindness, that's proof of god, Andy.
我從不會照顧自己 直到那天
I had never learned to take care of myself until that day,
我發現他們想把你占爲己有的那天
that day I found out they wanted you for their own.
我必須在我以前的生活和你之間做選擇
I had to choose my old life or you,
我選擇了你 安迪
and I chose you, Andy.
我現在又選擇了你
I'm choosing you again now.
別這樣...
Please...
太遲了 媽媽
It's too late, mom.
他太强大了
He's too big.
你進新學校時
Through the new schools
得水痘時 孤獨時
and the chickenpox and the loneliness,
他在哪
where was he?
他從沒露面
He never made an appearance,
只有現在
only now,
在我抗下了所有重擔之後
now that I've done all the heavy lifting.
好吧 我還沒抗完
Well, I'm not finished.
還輪不到他做選擇
He doesn't get to make the choice.
要做選擇的是你
You make it.
你要做出選擇
我愛你 媽媽
Love you, mom.
生日快樂
譯者:微博@Emtee